Hello everyone.
In this session, I will demo how to generate Testcase using GitHub Copilot.
To use this feature, I first need a Test Workspace Folder.
This folder is for the item for which I need to generate Testcase.
I will go to Testing Support.
Here, I will have two options.
The first option is to create a Test Workspace Folder for an item.
The second option is to create a Test Workspace Folder for a list of other items.
I will demo the first option first.
I will choose One Item here.
Here, I will have three types of information.
The first information is the database path.
This folder path contains the database loaded from the Stream or Snapshot.
The second information is the workspace path.
I will create a blank folder.
I will use this folder path to store the outputs generated while the tool is running.
The third information is the item name.
This is the item for which I need to create the Test Workspace Folder.
After filling in these three fields, I will click Generate Environment.
After this step is complete, the tool will show a notification.
At the same time, Visual Studio Code will open automatically.
It will import the Test Workspace Folder for the item.
Here, I will have the source file.
I will also have two files: test.cpp and test.h.
Besides, I can use the Open output feature.
It will open the Test Workspace Folder for the item I need to create.
For the second option, I will choose List Item.
I also have three important pieces of information.
The first is the database path.
The second is the workspace path.
The third is the List Items path.
I will have an Excel file containing the item name and item path information.
This identifies the items for which Test Workspace Folders need to be created.
Then I will take the path of this file.
I will enter it into the List Items path field.
Then I will click Generate Environment.
After this step is complete, choose Open output.
Then we will see the workspace folder created inside Item list.
After creating the Test Workspace Folder for the item, we need to create a testcase.
We choose Generate Test Case by A.I. Copilot.
Here, I have two fields.
The first one is the item path.
I will go to the Test Workspace Folder for the item that needs test cases generated.
For example, this item.
I will copy the path of this file.
After that, I will enter the first piece of information.
The next one is the database path.
This is just like the previous step.
I will also enter the folder containing the database.
Then I will click Auto Define Object.
While the tool is running, we can view detailed information.
Click Show Execution Log to display it.
A Terminal window will appear.
It will show detailed information while the tool is running.
After Auto Define Object is complete, we will go to the next step.
The next step is Prepare Get SUTs.
In the pop-up, we will see that it found three SUT functions.
The dropdown is also updated.
We can see the three functions listed here.
We will select one of the three functions for which we want to generate a test case.
Next, we will have two options.
The first option is to generate a test case for the selected function.
The second option is to generate test cases for all functions in this item.
To make the running process easier to observe, we will open Visual Studio Code.
Then we will import the Test Workspace Folder for the item.
Now we will demonstrate the first option.
To generate a test case for one function, we choose Generate one SUT.
We can see that the trigger to generate the testcase is sent here.
We will see the information in Visual Studio Code.
We will go to Output and choose GitHub Copilot Chat.
The generation process information will be shown in this Terminal.
We will see a notification when test generation is complete.
At that point, the generation process is done.
Next, we will click Terminal.
We will build this test.
Here, we have eight Testcases, and all eight Testcases have passed.
Next, we will check the code coverage.
Then we will proceed to build Cantata for this test.
We will click Build Cantata here.
After Build Cantata is complete, we will check the Test Workspace Folder.
Inside the Output folder, there is a Cantata folder.
We will open Cantata.
Click Tools.
Then we will go to the C folder.
Choose TCC.
Go to Tools.
Go to Cantata.
Then we will open this tool.
We will create a C Project in Cantata.
We will name the project after the item name.
We will drag the Cantata folder into the new project we just created in Cantata.
I will click this .cov file.
Then I will open this file.
Here, I can see that the code for the first function is green.
This means that these lines of code have been covered.
These red lines are still not covered.
Then I will demonstrate the second option, Generate Testcase All SUT.
Before clicking this Generate button, I will delete the newly created Testcases.
This prevents duplication in the next run.
Then I will click Generate Testcase All SUT.
This will create Testcases for all functions in this item.
After generating the testcases for all three functions in this item, I will build Cantata.
In this step, we can click Build Cantata to build in the tool.
Or we can build Cantata from Visual Studio Code.
I go to Terminal and select Run Task....
Then I select Cantata++ coverage measurement.
In the Terminal section, I can see the values.
The code coverage has reached 100%.
We will go to Cantata.
We will see that the code has 100% coverage.
I will gradually drag the Cantata folder into the project.
This is in the Cantata tool.
Here, we can see that the code in all three functions is already covered.
Therefore, their color changes to green.
Now we click Cantata and choose View.
Then choose Report Viewer to view this report.
We can view the test report here.
We can also see the coverage here.
This is the end of my demonstration.
Thank you for watching.